dennisorszulak.github.io (574) 904-3088

### **Software Developer**

Motivated Software Developer with Aerospace and Electronics industry experience. Strong track record of documenting processes while determining best practices to improve the end goals of projects. Demonstrated ability in developing applications and collaborating with staff and managers for project feedback. Adept at quickly learning new skills and technology due to a technology background and solid foundation in Electrical Engineering Technology.

### **Key Skills**

## **Programming Languages**

- Swift with iOS Framework
- Visual Basic for Applications
- C++ (Purdue)
- C (Purdue)

### **Applications**

- Xcode and Git
- National Instruments LabVIEW, Multisim and Ultiboard
- Autodesk Inventor
- Microsoft Office Suite

## Experience

## Honeywell Aerospace, South Bend, IN Senior Engineering Technician

July 2019 - May 2020

Created, modified, and implemented data acquisition systems to test fuel control systems used in the Aerospace industry.

- Implemented and connected data acquisition systems to the appropriate sensors and other electrical devices that were required to run environmental tests on fuel control systems.
- Modified and installed LabVIEW software for SCXI and PXI hardware for environmental test setups.
- Performed calibrations on data acquisition devices such as thermocouples, transducers, flow meters, and LVDT's.
- Recorded detailed documentation and wrote guides to promote standard work procedures regarding electrical work.
- Wrote a VBA script to automatically fill in required documents necessary for software modifications and upgrades.

## Electronics Inc., Mishawaka, IN

October 2016 - July 2019

Software Developer and Assistant Engineer, December 2017 - July 2019

Designed, developed, and tested the company's iOS app. Performed secondary duties in the engineering department for assisting with the design and tests of other electrical engineering projects.

- Solely developed the MagnaValve iOS app that controls a smart valve which is used in the shot peening and blast cleaning industry.
- Implemented Bluetooth Low Energy communication with CoreBluetooth, in addition to using custom JSON to receive and transmit data with the valve.

Dennis Orszulak Page Two

 Collaborated with the Android developer to match features, fix bugs on both platforms, and suggest improvements.

**Engineering Intern and Assistant Engineer,** October 2016 - December 2017 Assisted engineering projects to complete various designing and testing needs.

- Designed capacitive sensor circuitry prototypes with Multisim to monitor flow rates of nonferrous material through valves.
- Programmed a VBA script and macro for a terminal program called TeraTerm to automatically enter measured flow rates into Excel over many different valve settings.
- Tested, repaired, and recalibrated valves from customers that had damaged circuit boards.
- Corrected 3D models from engineering change requests using Autodesk Inventor CAD software.

## **Projects**

## **EE Number Cruncher,** Osceola, IN **iOS App Store Link**

- Created a helpful app that contains several calculators and converters for daily electrical engineering tasks.
- Implemented unit tests to verify correct answers on every calculator.
- Designed a clean, simple-to-use, and great-looking UI that is adaptable for many screen sizes via Interface Builder.

# **PLC Trainer,** South Bend, IN **Senior Design**

- Partnered with a fellow classmate and built an industrial PLC system that trains employees from a local company about basic troubleshooting principles and techniques.
- Created wiring diagrams, 3D drawings, a manual, and a final report for this senior design project.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering Technology
Purdue University South Bend

GPA: 3.91